

# **Matthew Lyon**

Manchester, United Kingdom

I am currently a PhD student in the Machine Learning group at the University of Manchester. My research focuses on improving MRI data through deep learning, and incorporating geometric priors into deep learning models. I have prior experience working as a research software engineer at several research institutes.

#### Education

2020 - present **United Kingdom**  **PhD in Computer Science,** *University of Manchester* 

2015 - 2016 Australia

Master of Medical Physics, University of Sydney

2011 - 2014**United Kingdom**  BSc (Hons) in Physics, University of Warwick

### **Professional Experience**

08/2019 - 08/2020 Sydney, Australia

**Research Software Engineer,** Save Sight Institute

Part Time 0.8 FTE

- Developed, tested, and documented neuroimaging processing pipelines.
- Lead algorithm design and optimisation workflows.
- Consulted on neuroimaging analysis techniques and signal processing.

08/2019 - 01/2020

Sydney, Australia

**Neuroimaging Analyst,** Sydney Neuroimaging Research Centre

Part Time 0.4 FTE

- Developed and implemented neuroimaging analysis pipelines.
- Performed QC on MRI analysis.

07/2017 - 07/2019 Sydney, Australia

**Research Software Engineer,** Heart Research Institute

Full Time

- Built and managed a distributed computing cluster.
- Developed, tested, and documented neuroimaging processing pipelines.
- Oversaw data ingestion and QC/QA, created dashboard visualisations.
- Conducted clinical research using MRI data.

## 🕱 Technologies

<b>□</b> Publication	s
2019	Gender-specific structural abnormalities in major depressive disorder revealed by fixel-based analysis, NeuroImage: Clinical Matthew Lyon, Thomas Welton, Adrina Varda, Jerome J. Maller, Kathryn Broadhouse, Mayuresh S. Korgaonkar, Stephen H. Koslow, Leanne M. Williams, Evian Gordon, A. John Rush, Stuart M. Grieve
2019	Is occipital bending a structural biomarker of risk for depression and sensitivity to treatment?, Journal of Clinical Neuroscience Karen Fullard, Jerome J. Maller, Thomas Welton, Matthew Lyon, Evian Gordon, Stephen H. Koslow, Stuart M. Grieve
2019	Profound and reproducible patterns of reduced regional gray matter characterize major depressive disorder, <i>Translational Psychiatry</i> Sarah C. Hellewell, Thomas Welton, Jerome J. Maller, Matthew Lyon, Mayuresh S. Korgaonkar, Stephen H. Koslow, Leanne M. Williams, John A. Rush, Evian Gordon, Stuart M. Grieve

## Courses

2019

10/2020	C++: From Beginner to Expert, Udemy
06/2020	Convolutional Neural Networks, Coursera
06/2020	Sequence Models, Coursera
02/2020	Neural Networks and Deep Learning, Coursera
01/2020	Machine Learning, Coursera

diffusion MRI study, Human Brain Mapping

Structural core of the executive control network: A high angular resolution

Kai-kai Shen, Thomas Welton, Matthew Lyon, Andrew N. McCorkindale, Greg T. Sutherland, Samantha Burnham, Jurgen Fripp, Ralph Martins, Stuart M. Grieve